law.ac.uk 2017-12-12

# Cookie & Privacy Policy | University of Law

##### What is a cookie?

A cookie is a type of information that a website puts on your computer, in order to remember something about you at a later time. When someone visits our website, we use cookies to track the number of visitors to our website and to help us to improve the overall visitor experience. These cookies do not collect or store any personally identifiable information. You may delete and block all cookies from this site, but parts of the site will not work. If you prefer for us to not collect cookies, you may refuse the use of cookies.

Most web browsers allow some control of most cookies through the browser settings. To find out more about cookies, including how to see what cookies have been set and how to manage and delete them, visit [www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/ "www.allaboutcookies.org - this link will open in a new window").

##### Overview

Our primary aim in collecting personal information is to provide you with a customised experience on our website - aiming to show you information that is relevant to you.

We also collect information for statistical purposes and to offer you future products and services that may be of interest to you.

##### Information we collect

  * Log file information, including IP addresses. You can visit public areas of the site without identifying yourself or providing any personal information
  * Tracking IP addresses (the computer's internet address)
  * Monitoring how long a user spends on the site and which pages he/she visits - this helps us evaluate the use of different parts of the website

As a rule, we don't link IP addresses to anything that can identify you personally, ensuring you can remain anonymous. Nevertheless, we will attempt to use IP addresses to identify a user when we feel it is necessary to protect our services and other users.

##### The cookies we use and why

**Cookie** | **Name** | **Purpose** | **More information**  
---|---|---|---  
Google Analytics | _utma   
_utmb   
_utmc   
_utmz   
| These cookies are used to collect information about how visitors use our site. We use the information to compile reports and to help us improve the site. The cookies collect information in an anonymous form, including the number of visitors to the site, where vistors have come to the site from and the pages they visited.   
  
ASP.Net session | ASP.NET_SessionId   
| This cookie is the default one used by ASPNET to uniquely identify the user's session on the site and relates the visitor's unique session to server side data. Our application uses the session to track the user's progress in wizards or for passing data which cannot be stored locally. The cookie will expire at the end of the session (when you close your internet browser).   
  
Ektron preferences | ecm | This cookie is used by the Ektron application, our Content Management System (CMS), to store information about the anonymous and logged in visitor. For authenticated users, the user id and a unique ID are stored, and compared with the values on the server to determine valid authentication.   
|    
Ektron user ID | EKTGUID   
| This cookie is used to track visitors to the site. A unique identifier for the current visitor is generated for all visitors, including anonymous visitors, and assigned to the visitor at the time they first arrive on the site. We use this information to uniquely identify the user when they perform unauthenticated actions on the site, such as commenting on content, and also to compile reports on visitor usage. This cookie expires after 1 year.   
|    
Ektron analytics overlay | ektron_analytics_overlay  | This cookie is set by the overlay system to store whether the overlay is enabled, and which overlay view to show. This cookie is enabled only for users with permissions to see the overlay.  |    
Ektron analytics segment | EktronGoogle-AnalyticsSegmentFilterIds   
| This cookie is set by the analytics reporting system, and only used by authenticated users who view analytics data. The cookie defines what segment ID the user is currently viewing analytics data with.   
|    
Ektron site cookie acceptance | ecmCookiesAccepted   
| This cookie is used to record if a user has accepted the use of cookies on the website.   
|    
  
##### Google Analytics

This website uses Google Analytics, a web analytics service provided by Google, Inc. (“Google”). Google Analytics uses cookies (text files placed on your computer) to help the website operators analyse how users use the site. The information generated by the cookie about your use of the website (including your IP address) will be transmitted to and stored by Google on servers in the United States. Google will use this information for the purpose of evaluating your use of the website, compiling reports on website activity for website operators and providing other services relating to website activity and internet usage. Google may also transfer this information to third parties where required to do so by law, or where such third parties process the information on Google's behalf. Google will not associate your IP address with any other data held by Google. By using this website, you consent to the processing of data about you by Google in the manner and for the purposes set out above.

To opt out of being tracked by Google Analytics across all websites visit [http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout "Google Analytics Opt-out Browser Add-on - this link will open in a new window").

##### Third party sites

Please be aware that some of the websites to which we provide links may collect personally identifiable information about you. We do not control these sites and are not responsible for the content or practices of third party websites. This privacy policy does not cover such sites.

For information on our FAQ’s supplier Right Now -   
<http://www.oracle.com/us/legal/privacy/privacy-policy-078584.html>

For information on our email marketing software supplier Oracle -  
<http://www.oracle.com/us/legal/privacy/privacy-policy/index.html>   

##### Social media cookies

The University of Law is active on a range of social media platforms. We have no control over the use of cookies on these third party sites. Please follow these links for more information on the privacy policies of the individual social media sites where The University of Law is active:

  * Facebook - [http://www.facebook.com/about/privacy/](https://www.facebook.com/about/privacy/ "Facebook Privacy Policy - this link will open in a new window")
  * Twitter - <https://twitter.com/privacy>
  * YouTube - [http://www.youtube.com/static?hl=en&template=privacy](http://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/ "YouTube Privacy Policy - this link opens in a new window")
  * LiveStream - <http://www.livestream.com/terms/privacypolicy>
  * LinkedIn - [http://www.linkedin.com/static?key=privacy_policy](http://www.linkedin.com/legal/privacy-policy "LinkedIn Privacy Policy - this link opens in a new window")

##### YouTube cookies

We embed videos from our official YouTube channel using YouTube’s privacy-enhanced mode. This mode may set cookies on your computer once you click on the YouTube video player, but YouTube will not store personally-identifiable cookie information for playbacks of embedded videos using the privacy-enhanced mode.

##### Search engine

The search engine on our website is designed to be as powerful and easy to use as the popular search engine Google. The search is made possible by a piece of hardware (a search ‘appliance’) supplied by Google that is plugged into our server and continuously indexes the content on our site. All search requests are handled by the appliance and the information is not passed on to any third party, including Google.

We are aware that you may have concerns over disclosing information about yourself to us.

This privacy policy explains, amongst other things, what information we collect about you on this website and the reasons for this.

##### How to refuse the use of cookies

You may refuse the use of cookies by selecting the appropriate settings in your browser. However, if you do this you may lose some useful functionality such as login features.

##### How to disable cookies in your browser

Here's how to prevent new cookies from being installed and how to delete existing cookies. The exact procedure depends on which browser you are using.

  * Internet Explorer 9.0+
  * Internet Explorer 8.0+
  * Internet Explorer 7.0+
  * Firefox 2.0+, 3.0+, 4.0+
  * Google Chrome
  * Safari

##### Internet Explorer 9.0+

 **To prevent new cookies from being installed**

  * Go to Tools in the menu bar
  * Click on Internet Options
  * Click on the Privacy tab on top
  * Move the slider up to the "Block all Cookies" button

 **To delete existing cookies**

  * Go to Tools in the menu bar
  * Click on Internet Options
  * Click on the General tab which should be under "Browsing History" and click "Delete"

##### Internet Explorer 8.0+

 **To prevent new cookies from being installed**

  * Go to Tools in the menu bar
  * Click on Internet Options
  * Click on the Privacy tab on top
  * Click on "Sites"
  * A new window should open called "Per Site Privacy Actions"
  * Type in the URL of the site in the "Address of website" box and click on Block

 **To delete existing cookies**

  * Go to Tools in the menu bar
  * Click on 'Internet Options'
  * Click on the Privacy tab on top
  * Click on "Sites"
  * A new window should open called "Per Site Privacy Actions"
  * Under the "Managed websites" box should be a list of all the websites you have visited
  * To remove all cookies click on the "Remove all" button

##### Internet Explorer 7.0+

 **To prevent new cookies from being installed**

  * Go to Tools in the menu bar
  * Click on Options
  * Click on the Privacy tab on top
  * Click on the Advanced button
  * Select "Prompt" for both "First party cookies" and "Third Party Cookies"

 **To delete existing cookies**

  * Go to Tools in the menu bar
  * Click on Options
  * Click on the General tab on top
  * In the "Browsing History" section, click on "Delete"
  * Click on "Delete Cookies"

##### Firefox 2.0+, 3.0+, 4.0+

 **To prevent new cookies from being installed**

  * Go to Tools in the menu bar
  * Click on Options
  * Click on the Privacy tab
  * Disable the box that says "Accept Cookies From sites"

 **To delete existing cookies**

  * Go to Tools in the menu bar
  * Click on Options
  * Click on the Privacy tab
  * Click on "Clear Now"
  * Select "Cookies"
  * Click on "Clear Private Data Now"

##### Google Chrome

 **To prevent new cookies from being installed**

  * Click on the spanner icon in the top right of the browser
  * Click on "Options"
  * Click on "Under the Bonnet" (UK) / "Under the Hood" (US)
  * Click on the "Content settings" button in the Privacy section
  * Ensure that "Allow local data to be set" is selected
  * Select "Block sites from setting any data"

 **To delete existing cookies**

  * Click on the spanner icon in the top right of the browser
  * Click on "Options"
  * Click on "Under the Bonnet" (UK) / "Under the Hood" (US)
  * Click on the "Content settings" button in the Privacy section
  * Click on the "Clear browsing data" button

##### Safari

 **To prevent new cookies from being installed and delete existing cookies**

  * Go to the Safari menu (icon in top right of browser) and select Preferences
  * In the popup window that appears, select the Security icon (a padlock)
  * Under "Accept Cookies", select the "Never" button

##### Personal data

Any personal data relating to you gathered by us in the registration process or during your use of the service will be recorded and only be used in accordance with our Data Protection Policy.

The website uses various order and registration forms to enable you to request information, products and services.

Then you register for the secure sections of our website you will need to provide us with information such as your name, e-mail address and password.

Any personal data we collect during registration is designed to allow us to personalise the site for you and give you access to the right kinds of information.

If you register, request further information or contact us we may keep a record of that correspondence and incorporate the information it contains into our database(s).

Please be aware that when you receive a call from The University of Law it may be monitored and recorded. This is to be used internally for record-keeping, training and quality-assurance purposes.

##### Internet security

The web server that hosts this site is not used to store personal information of any kind.

Any personal information that you do provide is stored on a separate and secure database server within the University's firewall. There is no direct link between this database server and the internet and access is strictly limited to internal University IT staff and authorised site administrators only.

Access to certain areas of the site is limited to specific registered user groups only. Registering as an accepted applicant or active is restricted; we will verify your status before granting a user account of this type. If your status changes then your user account may be withdrawn or downgraded to 'general visitor' without further notice.

Whilst we do not directly track or record your usage of this website, in the event that we become aware that site security has been compromised as a result of external activity (including but not limited to external security attacks) we shall take reasonable measures which we deem appropriate. This includes but is not limited to internal investigation and reporting, and notification to and cooperation with law enforcement authorities.

This privacy policy may not apply to you if we believe you are misusing the website or if we are required to disclose information by a court of law or other relevant body.

More information on the data protection policy
